Guide to the Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1, Section 3: Boxes 45-66
5583/1
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
120 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
Due to the volume of material in this collection the finding aid has been divided into six sections.
Section 1: Boxes 1-22
Section 2: Boxes 23-44
Section 3: Boxes 45-66
Section 4: Boxes 67-88
Section 5: Boxes 89-110
Section 6: Boxes 111-121
SUBJECTS
Names:
A. Philip Randolph Institute.; Abbott Laboratories.; Abbott Laboratories. House Organs.; Abraham & Straus.; Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation.; Administrative Management Society.; Adult Education Association.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Aerojet-General Corporation.; Aeroquip Corporation.; Aerospace Industries Association of America.; Aetna Life Insurance Company (Hartford, Conn.); Affiliated Schools for Workers.; African- American Labor Center.; Agway Inc.; Air Reduction Company.; Air Transport Association of America.; Airlines Negotiating Committee.; Alaska. Department of Administration.Division of Personnel.; Alden's, Inc.; Alexander Smith & Sons, Carpet Co.; Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corporation.; Allegheny Metal.; Allied Chemical & Dye Corporation; Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company.; Aluminum Company of America.; American Arbitration Association.; American Brake Shoe Company.; American Can Company.; American Labor Education Service.; American Locomotive Company.; American Management Association.; American Merchant Marine Institute.; American Metal Climax, Inc.; American Motors Corporation.; American Petroleum Institute.; American Plan Association.; American Society of Safety Engineers.; American Telephone and Telegraph Company.; American Textile Manufacturers Institute.; American Thread Company.; American Trucking Associations.; American Type Founders Company.; American Vocational Association.; Americans Against Union Control of Government.; Amtrak.; Anaconda American Brass Company.; Anaconda Company.; Anaconda Copper Mining Company.; Anaconda Wire and Cable Company.; Anchor Hocking Glass Corporation.; Armco Steel Corporation.; Armour and Company.; Armstrong Cork Company.; Associated Builders & Contractors (U.S.); Associated General Contractors of America.; Association of American Railroads.; Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Company.; Atlantic Refining Company.; Atlas Chemical Industries.; ATO, Inc.; Automobile Manufacturers Association.; Automotive and Aviation Parts Manufacturers.; Automotive Council for War Production.; Bell & Howell Co.; Bell Aircraft Corporation.; Bell of Pennsylvania.; Bell Telephone Company.; Bell Telephone Laboratories.; Bethlehem Steel Corporation.; Bird and Son, Inc.; Bituminous Coal Operators' Association.; Bloomer Brothers.; Boeing Aerospace Company.; Boeing Company.; Borden Company.; Brockway Glass Company.; Building Trades Employers' Association.; Bureau of National Affairs (Arlington, Va.); Burlington Industries, Inc.; Burndy Engineering Company.; Burrough Corporation.; California Institute of Technology. Industrial Relations Center.; California Institute of Technology.; California State Personnel Board.; Canadian National Railways; Canadian Pacific Railway Company.; Carborundum Company (Niagara Falls, N.Y.); Carnation Company.; Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation.; Carrier Corporation.; Caterpillar Tractor Company.; Celanese Corporation.; Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation.; Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America.; Chemical Corn Exchange Bank.; Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Maryland.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company of Virginia.; Chesapeake and Potomac Telephone Company.; Chessie System, inc.; Chicago Transit Authority.; Chrysler Corporation.; Cincinnati Bell Inc.; Civil Service Assembly of the United States and Canada.; Climax Molybdenum Company.; Clothing Manufacturers Association of the U.S.A.; Colgate-Palmolive Company.; Colorado Fuel and Iron Company.; Columbia Gas Company.; Commerce and Industry Association of New York.; Committee for the Nation's Health.; Commonwealth Edison Company.; Communications Workers of America.; Cone Mills Corporation.; Connecticut General Life Insurance Company.; Consolidated Edison Company of New York, inc.; Consolidated Gas, Electric Light, and Power Company of Baltimore.; Consolidated Natural Gas Company.; Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation.; Consumers' League of New York City.; Consumers Power Company (Mich.); Container Corporation of America.; Continental Can Company.; Continental Insurance Company.; Continental Oil Company.; Cooperative League of the U.S.A.; Corn Products Refining Company.; Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory.; Cornell University.; Corning Glass Works.; Council Against Communist Aggression (U.S.); Council for International Progress in Management (USA); Council of Profit Sharing Industries (U.S.); Crane Co.; Crane Packing Co.; Credit Union National Association.; Crouse-Hinds Company.; Crown Zellerbach Corporation.; Crucible Steel Company of America.; Dan River Mills Inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Daystrom, inc.; Dartnell Corporation.; Deere & Company.; Detroit Edison Company.; Diamond Alkali Company.; Dictaphone Corp.; Dole Food Company.; Douglas Aircraft Company.; Dow Chemical Company.; E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Company.; Eagle Pencil Company.; Eastern Gas and Fuel Associates.; Eastern Western & Southwestern Canier Company.; Eastman Kodak Company.; Eaton Corporation.; Eaton Manufacturing Company.; Ecusta Paper Company.; Electronic Industries Alliance.; Eli Lilly and Company.; Employers' Association of Chicago.; Employers' Association of Detroit.; Employers' Association of Grand Rapids.; Employers' Association of Massachusetts.; Employers' Association of Milwaukee.; Employers' Association of Pittsburgh.; Employers' Association of Washington.; Employers' Group of Insurance Companies.; Employers' Labor Relations Information Committee.; Employers' of Mutual of Wasau.; Engineers Joint Council. Engineering Manpower Commission.; Erie Railroad Company.; Erie-Lackawanna Railroad Company.; Erlanger Mills, Inc.; Erwin Cotton Mills.; Esso Research and Engineering Company.; Esso Standard Oil Company.; Exxon Corporation; Falstaff Brewing Corporation; Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America; Federal Professional Association (U.S.); Federal Reserve Bank of New York; Federated Employers of San Francisco; Federated Employers of the Bay Area; Fieldcrest Mills Inc.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Firestone Tire and Rubber Company; First National Bank (Ithaca, N.Y.); First National Bank Maryland; First National Bank of Boston; First National Bank of Chicago; First National Bank of Portland (Portland, Me.); First National Bank of St. Louis; First Pennsylvania Bank, N.A.; First Pennsylvania Banking and Trust Company, Philadelphia.; Fischer and Porter Company; Florida Power & Light Company; Ford Foundation; Ford Motor Company; Foster and Forbes Glass Company; Foundation for Economic Education, inc.; General Dynamics Corporation.; General Electric Company; George Fischer, Ltd.; J.N. Adam & Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New York Chamber of Commerce.; Society for Equitable Assurances on Lives and Survivorships.; South Central Bell.; University of California, Berkeley. Institute of Industrial Relations.; William Filene's Sons Co.; Commonwealth Edison Company; A. Philip Randolph Institute; ATO, Inc.; Aero Supply Mfg. Co.; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
Subjects:
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Audio equipment industry; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer protection; Container industry; Credit unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents); Publications (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Other sections of this Collection:
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 1: Boxes 1-22
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 2: Boxes 23-44
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 4: Boxes 67-88 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 5: Boxes 89-110
5583/1: Archives Organization File (AFF) Part 1, Section 6: Boxes 111-121
Related Collections:
5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents
5583/2: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3
5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications
5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5
5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6
5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
CONTAINER LIST
- Box: 45, Folder: 1 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. v.1:no.3 (1957:May/June). Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. First Quarter, 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. First Quarter, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Third Quarter, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Fourth Quarter, 1964. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Third Quarter, 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Fourth Quarter, 1965. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. First Quarter, 1966. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Third Quarter, 1966. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Fourth Quarter, 1966. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. First Quarter, 1967. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Third Quarter, 1967. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. Fourth Quarter, 1967. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Perspective, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. First Quarter, 1968. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Cornell Aeornautical Laboratory An Evaluation, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. December 31, 1955. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Lab League News, Publication (Box 45, Folder 1)
    By Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory. v.7:no.3 (1951:Aug.). Item is in English.
- Box: 45, Folder: 2 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Yours Truly, Publication (Box 45, Folder 2)
    By Corn Products Refining Company. October, 1954. Item is in English.
- Box: 45, Folder: 3 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Wage Differences, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By N. Arnold Tolles. March 1949. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Program suggestions prepared for the International Association of Machinists, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell University New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations. November 1949. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Extension Lecture Number 1, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Vernon H. Jensen. Elmira College, Elmira, NY, November 10, 1947. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Letters from the People, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Brobury Pearce Ellis; Mary Ellen Rossiter; Robert N. Hampton. December 5, 1950. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Letters from the People, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Roger Baldwin; John Schappi, Jr.; Samuel P. Horton. December 6, 1950. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Express Concern, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. May 20, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: The Black Studies Thing, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ernest Dunbar. April 6, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: C.U. Staff on Strike, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Committee of Concerned Non-Academic Employees. May 6, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Straight Boycot Readied, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Barbara Kantrowitz. v.84:no.33 (1969:Oct. 24). News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 10: Boycott, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell Daily Sun. v.84:no.33 (1969:Oct. 24). News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 11: Cornell Files Petition With NLRB, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell Daily Sun. September 20, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 12: Cornell Anti-War Employes, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Marty Robbs; Robert Radford. May 27, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 13: Cornell to Recruit Minorities, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. November 12, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 14: Peterson Issues Employment Memo, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell Chronicle. June 4, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 15: Letter to editor on status of Cornell University Librarians, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Shirley C. Spragge. July 30, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 16: Boycott W.S.H. Today, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    Item is in English.
  - Item 17: Job Security? Workers Students Management a Discussion, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Item 18: NLRB to Get Hearing Data, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Patricia Nordheimer. November 8, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 19: NLRB Hearing Continues, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Patricia Nordheimer. November 7, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 20: Hearings Question NLRB Control, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Rebecca Singer; Judith Greenhill. November 6, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 21: Cornell Labor Law Hearing Scheduled, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Patricia Nordheimer. November 11, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 22: NLRB to Oversee Cornell Collective Bargaining, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Helen Mundell. June 16, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: Union Vote July 16, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. June 19, 1970. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 24: NLRB Heaing Continues, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Patricia Nordheimer. November 6, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 25: Boycott of Noyes Center Fails, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Barbara Kantroqitz. October 28, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 26: Board to Name Appropritate Bargain Unit for Libe Employees, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Michael Chenkin. May 8, 1969. News clipping. Photocopy. Item is in English.
  - Item 27: Group Votes To Continue H&D Boycott, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Barbara Kantrowitz. v.84:No.34 (1969:Oct. 27). News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 28: WSH Workers Protest Layoff Of Full-tome Dining Employees, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Barbara Kantrowitz. v.84:no.32 (1969:Oct. 23). News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 29: Text of Student Committee Statement, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. December 1, 1950. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 30: Trustees Asked To Act On Strike, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 31: Labor Hearing Continues To Decide NLRB Status, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell Daily Sun. November 7, 1969. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 32: Cornell Service Employee Strike, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell University. November 29, 1950. News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 33: Hiring, Representation Discussion by Task Force, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Judith Greenhill. April 30. News clipping. Photocopy. Item is in English.
  - Item 34: NLRB Shifts Stand, Takes College Units, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Eugene A. Kelly. June 20, 1970. News clipping. Photocopy. Item is in English.
  - Item 35: Oppose Strike, Back Plan, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. May 15, 1969, News clipping. Item is in English.
  - Item 36: Grad Students Move To Join AFT Union, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Donna B. Greenberg. April 18, 1969. News clipping. Photocopy. Item is in English.
  - Item 37: Bulletin, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Cornell University Libraries. no.149 (1969:Nov. 23). Item is in English.
  - Item 38: Employes, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Robert Radford. May 11, 1970. Item is in English.
  - Item 39: National Grange Protests, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. January 19, 1971. Item is in English.
  - Item 40: Grange Raps Lettuce Boycott, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ithaca Journal. January 9, 1971. Item is in English.
  - Item 41: Chavez Is Happy, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ellen Berle. January 9, 1971. Item is in English.
  - Item 42: Lettuce Bowl: Cornell Grange Opposed on Issue, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By Ellen Berle. January 20, 1971. Item is in English.
  - Item 43: The Story of Statler Hall, Publication (Box 45, Folder 3)
    By J. Knight Willy. Reprinted form The Hotel Monthly, August 1950. Item is in English.
- Box: 45, Folder: 4 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Cornell University Press 90th Anniversary 1969-1959, Publication (Box 45, Folder 4)
    By Cornell University Press. Item is in English.
- Box: 45, Folder: 5 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Laboratory Glass Blowing with PYREX brand Glasses, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Laboratory and Pharmaceutical Sales Department. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: A Short Story of Technical Glassware, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Corning Glass Works. PYREX. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Glass and You, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Corning Glass Works. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Educational Report, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Corning Glass Works. Corning Glass Works Training Program; L. W. Larson, Supervisor of Training. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Chemistry of Glass, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By W. C. Taylor. Paper Given at Glass Container Association Meeting, Montreal, Canada; September 28, 1928. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: They Live in a Glass House and Like It, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Arthur W. Baum. Reprinted from THE SATURDAY EVENING POST. Item is in English.
  - Item 7: Pension Plan, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Corning Glass Works. Effective January 1, 1944. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Distrobution of Functions; Corning glass Works Plants, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Organization & Eval. Revised July 8, 1963. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Opportunities at Corning; technicians; computer operators; secretarial science, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: Research and Development, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: Corning Benefits, Publication (Box 45, Folder 5)
    By Corning Glass Works. April, 1973. Item is in English.